{
    "id": "ed98b3c4c1fd468ab2358c507701f435",
    "title": "Present Perfect Or Simple Past Tense Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She ...................... to anybody in her life.",
            "description": "The present perfect is more common with time expressions like ever, never, yet, before and already.",
            "answers": [
                "never apologized",
                "has never apologized",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e2807bc0c64b476da30185d7ee405bad"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am sure we ……………… before.",
            "description": "The present perfect is more common with time expressions like ever, never, yet, before and already.",
            "answers": [
                "never met",
                "have never met",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a64f9be2ad634712ab13a68c174cd95c"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………. a word with the manager in the morning.",
            "description": "The present perfect is not used to talk about a finished event if we say when it happened.",
            "answers": [
                "had",
                "have had",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1e7e936988dd4def871f59d9d092f3c1"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………….. two movies yesterday.",
            "description": "The present perfect is not used to talk about a finished event if we say when it happened.",
            "answers": [
                "watched",
                "have watched",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "eab27e16cb514f7ea6b537f42ba03b58"
        },
        {
            "question": "How long ………………….. in love with him?",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about how long present situations have lasted.",
            "answers": [
                "were you",
                "have you been",
                "are you"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5828c4b288854f27a3cbe390399ac8cb"
        },
        {
            "question": "She …………… at thirty-nine.",
            "description": "The present perfect is not used to talk about a finished event if we say when it happened. ",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "dead",
                "has died"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c79157de4e3d4a0bbbf7693c84952826"
        },
        {
            "question": "The number of unemployed ……………….. ten million.",
            "description": "The present perfect is the most normal tense for giving news of recent events.",
            "answers": [
                "reached",
                "has reached",
                "had reached"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4ce96742b4544474896948b1164ed37c"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………….. the people who live next door?",
            "description": "The present perfect is more common with the indefinite time expressions ever, never, yet, already.",
            "answers": [
                "Did you ever meet",
                "Have you ever met",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bdb158131fb147af960d3f3375eb49da"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Defense Minister …………… a meeting with the Prime Minister yesterday.",
            "description": "We do not use the present perfect tense with past time expressions. ",
            "answers": [
                "had",
                "has had",
                "had had"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8cdd81a66bd24cbb82c8306cb3c3c36a"
        },
        {
            "question": "During the two hour meeting, they ……………. the economic situation.",
            "description": "The present perfect is not used when the reference is to the past time. ",
            "answers": [
                "discussed",
                "have discussed",
                "had discussed"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4959bb21e22e41fdb7459c1901636c00"
        },
        {
            "question": "We …………….. that you have homes to let.",
            "description": "Sometimes past and present perfect are both possible.",
            "answers": [
                "heard",
                "have heard",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a360d46d717e4b20b960abedc2b6e541"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who …………….. the telephone?",
            "description": "We use the simple past when we ask about the person responsible for a present situation.",
            "answers": [
                "invented",
                "has invented",
                "had invented"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "978cc009f3c24476b2da9d6501fdb66d"
        }
    ]
}